## **Shahrukh Ahmed**

Web Developer

### **About**

I have been building websites for 3 years now. Most have been personal projects (links in the website) to get an educational website up and going. After giving it a shot, I am back in the jobmarket and I want to give webdevelopment as a career a go. It's a field that I find myself excited about because of the avenues available to learn. experiment and build something worthwhile. And I hope to do it in a professional capacity in the near future.

### Contact













## Skills

- HTML
- JavaScript
- CSS3
- Vue.js
- Django
- Bootstrap
- D3.js
- SVG
- Jquery
- React.js

## **Work Experience**

## Self-Employed & Freelance Web Development August 2015 - current

- Built, run and maintained numerous CRUD application for a personal projects.
- Designed UX and UI prototypes.
- · Built backend system with Django for CRUD apps, customising the admin system for easy entry, updation and deletion.
- Optimised the websites for SEO and speed ranking
- · Built a recommendation system for demo e-commerce project with vue.js that had a recommendation system based on fuzzy-logic.

# **Freelance Writing**

July 2015 - current

I have freelanced for local and international clients. I have written about current-affairs, healthcare, history, entertainment but the bulk of my work has been writing about Climate Change and renewable energy sources. My work typically involves going through dozens of research papers and writing an article that makes a topic easy and clear for the readers to grasp.

### Yahoo!

### August 2014 - June 2015

At Yahoo, I worked as a SEM analyst providing account management support to Advertisers. The role primarily included:

- Working with the Account managers and Account Operation Specialists in USA and Canada and providing them with Account Management support.
- Creating, Uploading and maintaining Advertiser Campaigns and various Search Ad formats.
- Finding Account Optimization opportunities to increase advertiser spend and improve account performance
- · Quarterly Performance review and competitive insight decks for clients.

## Education

#### MBA, PESIT

August 2012 - June 2014

#### B-Tech, VTU

August 2007 - Dec 2011